

SOHEL AHMED **ANSARI**

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

+971564710320 sohel.ahmed.ansari@gmail.com Dubai

WEBSITES & SOCIAL LINKS

Website:

https://sohelansari.com

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sohela

nsari

Stackoverflow:

https://stackoverflow.com/users/22

79116/shinobi

SKILLS

React
Redux
Knockout.Js
JQuery
Angularjs
Nodejs
Javascript (ES6)
HTML
CSS (Less)
Webpack
TypeScript

ABOUT ME

Experienced in everything from converting designs into functional pages to setting up complex applications in modern frameworks.

Specialized in handling front-end development and dealing with UI and UX of anything that I work on. I am always interested to put my views on the look and feel of the product.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR PROGRAMMER

ONE.COM | DUBAI MAY 2016 - PRESENT

Working on front-end and backend development of Webshop

(https://www.one.com/en/webshop)

Front-end is implemented using Knockout.js, backend is in Node.js and database in PostgreSQL.

We are now gradually re-writing this in React.

My role includes:

- Developing pixel perfect UI from given design and making it functional in React
- Fixing bugs in existing Knockout.js code.
- Converting Knockout.js code to React.
- Writing handlers in backend which is in Node.js and familiar with writing queries in PostgreSQL.
- Have worked on integrating payments through Credit card, iDEAL and Giropay using Stripe
- Acting as the communicator between my team of 5 developers with me in Dubai and the Project Manager in Copenhagen.
- Responsible for keeping an eye on the progress of the Sprint and making sure that the product manager is informed about any changes in it.
- Follow scrum methodology and Agile Software Development strategy.

Technologies include: React, Knockout.js, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, NodeJS, PostgreSQL

SENIOR PROGRAMMER

NEXSALES CORPORATION | MUMBAI NOV 2014 - APR 2016

Worked on front-end development of a web app VoiceReach used by BPO for reaching out to prospects for marketing.

It was a single page web application written in $\,$ AngularJS 1.3 $\,$

My role included:

- Getting involved in feature discussions and giving inputs on the UI/UX.
- Developing in AngularJS which includes creating HTML templates, styling CSS, writing code for angular controller, directive and services.
- Integrating external angular directives and using it.
- Follow scrum methodology and Agile Software Development strategy.

Technologies include: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, AngularJS 1.3, Bootstrap, NodeJS

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING SR. ANALYST

ACCENTURE | MUMBAI FEB 2014 - NOV 2014

Worked on front-end development of a retail company client. Work included making templates for given psds and making it functional. Making sure the page is responsive on all devices.

Technologies include: HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Sass, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Backbone.js

SENIOR PROGRAMMER

ZEUS SYSTEMS PVT. LTD. | MUMBAI JUL 2009 - JAN 2014

Worked on many e-learning products to help kids of different age groups learn Maths and Science.

Technologies include: HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Backbone.js, ActionScript 3, Flash

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

M.H. SABOO SIDDIK COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING | MUMBAI 2009